const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of these treatment options is the first line for mitral stenosis with significant symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"No management needed","bool":false},{"option":"Balloon valvuloplasty","bool":true},{"option":"Open commissurotomy","bool":false},{"option":"Valve replacement","bool":false},{"option":"Heart transplant","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"A 23-year-old primigravida, at 28 weeks of gestation, presents with shortness of breath. On examination, she has a loud S1 and an erratic pulse. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Normal pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Mild anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"A 15-year-old male patient with a history of fever, joint pain, and sore throat has \r\n now developed a murmur. Which of the following diseases presents with these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic fever","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Post streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"A patient who is a known case of diabetes mellitus and hypertension, with a history of cerebrovascular events one year ago, presented to the emergency department of a tertiary care hospital with a myocardial infarction within an hour of symptom onset. What is the best management for him?","answers":[{"option":"IV heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Aggressive medical management","bool":false},{"option":"Percutaneous coronary intervention","bool":true},{"option":"Thrombolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin and metoprolol","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following statements is most appropriate regarding atrial septal defects?","answers":[{"option":"It has a poor prognosis","bool":false},{"option":"It presents with cyanosis at birth","bool":false},{"option":"ECG is diagnostic","bool":false},{"option":"It is associated with systolic flow murmur over the aortic valve","bool":false},{"option":"Fixed splitting of S2 heart sound","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding pleural effusion associated with heart failure?","answers":[{"option":"Responds to diuretics","bool":true},{"option":"Predominantly serosal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amber colored","bool":false},{"option":"Exudative","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Pistol-shot femoral pulse is associated with which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Tricuspid regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":true},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following best describes the effect of venous return on the murmur of hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Increases with increased venous return","bool":false},{"option":"Increases with decreased venous return","bool":true},{"option":"Increases with standing","bool":false},{"option":"Increases with hand grip","bool":false},{"option":"Increases with squatting","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is most appropriate regarding hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Asymmetrical hypertrophy of ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Arrhythmias are refractory to treatment with amiodarone","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Mimics aortic regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Transthoracic echocardiography for diagnosis","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Migratory arthritis is found in which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Osteoarthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic fever","bool":true},{"option":"Sydenham's chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Reiter's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Gout","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Duroziez's sign in aortic regurgitation is seen due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Loud S1 sound","bool":false},{"option":"Crescendo-decrescendo murmur","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic bruit","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid bruit","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral bruit","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"A patient presents to the emergency with signs of myocardial infarction. ECG showed diffuse ST and T wave changes on leads V2-V4. What will be the most accurate diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Widespread anterior myocardial infarction","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Dressler's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"A patient with acute coronary syndrome has an electrocardiogram showing ST elevation. Angiography is normal, and echocardiography shows mild left ventricular dysfunction with a somewhat sustained ejection fraction. What will be the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Apical dyskinesia","bool":true},{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Carey Coombs murmur is due to a pathology in which of the following valves?","answers":[{"option":"Tricuspid","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary","bool":false},{"option":"Both mitral and tricuspid","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is responsible for fixed splitting of S2?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":true},{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is used for pain associated with pericarditis?","answers":[{"option":"Paracetamol","bool":false},{"option":"Immunosuppressants","bool":false},{"option":"NSAIDs","bool":true},{"option":"Colchicine","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"What will be the best treatment for angina?","answers":[{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Nitroglycerin","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium channel blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"A pregnant woman presents to the hospital with complaints of palpitations. On examination, she has a loud S1, and a mid diastolic murmur. What could be the cause?","answers":[{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is the investigation of choice for acute rheumatic fever?","answers":[{"option":"Blood culture","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal swab","bool":false},{"option":"Echocardiography","bool":true},{"option":"Cardiac enzymes","bool":false},{"option":"Electrocardiogram","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"A patient presents to the outpatient department with complaints of dyspnea, angina and syncope for the past few weeks. What could be the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Unstable angina","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"A 53-year-old Caucasian man presents to the clinic with a 3-year history of poorly controlled hypertriglyceridemia. Labs show fasting serum cholesterol=250 mg/dl (normal value <200mg/dL), triglycerides= 928 mg/dl (normal value=<150 mg/dl), and high-density lipoprotein (HDL)= 27 mg/dl (normal=40-60mg/dl). Which of the following is the best treatment option for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Ezetimibe","bool":false},{"option":"Colesevelam","bool":false},{"option":"Propranolol","bool":false},{"option":"Gemfibrozil","bool":true},{"option":"Atorvastatin","bool":false}]}]
export default arr